{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "51.As per a Supreme Court bench ruling, it can use its powers under which Article to directly granta divorce decree?",
            "options": [
                "Article 21",
                "Article 92",
                "Article 121",
                "Article 142"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Article 142"
        },
        {
            "question": "52.Mahi Banswara Atomic Power Project is being constructed in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Rajasthan",
                "Madhya Pradesh",
                "Punjab",
                "West Bengal"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Rajasthan"
        },
        {
            "question": "53.What is the name of the oscillations that are amplitude-modulated structured narrow-bandsignals?",
            "options": [
                "Geomagnetic Pc1 pearl oscillations",
                "Geomagnetic Pc1 gold oscillations",
                "Geomagnetic Pc1 silver oscillations",
                "Geomagnetic Pc1 diamond oscillations"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Geomagnetic Pc1 pearl oscillations"
        },
        {
            "question": "54.Which institution organises the \u2018Ekta Evam Shradhanjali Abhiyan\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "DRDO",
                "ISRO",
                "BRO",
                "BARC"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "BRO"
        },
        {
            "question": "55.Which institution developed the \u2018StarBerrySense\u2019 sensor?",
            "options": [
                "IIT Madras",
                "IISc Bengaluru",
                "IIA",
                "NIT Warangal"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IIA"
        },
        {
            "question": "56.Which city hosted the \u2018Yoga Mahotsav\u2019, to commemorate 50-day countdown to the InternationalDay of Yoga?",
            "options": [
                "New Delhi",
                "Jaipur",
                "Guwahati",
                "Bhopal"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Jaipur"
        },
        {
            "question": "57.\u2018Leptestheria chalukyae\u2019, which was recently discovered in Karnataka, belongs to which species?",
            "options": [
                "Spider",
                "Turtle",
                "Shrimp",
                "Snake"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Shrimp"
        },
        {
            "question": "58.The Smart Cities Mission has been extended from June 2023 to which year?",
            "options": [
                "2024",
                "2025",
                "2027",
                "2030"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "2024"
        },
        {
            "question": "59.Which institution developed a catalyst that can release hydrogen from wood alcohol withoutproducing carbon dioxide?",
            "options": [
                "IIT Madras",
                "IIT Delhi",
                "IIT Guwahati",
                "IIT Kharagpur"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IIT Guwahati"
        },
        {
            "question": "60.Ministry of External Affairs along with its counterpart of which country launched a foundation topromote dialogue between youth leaders?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "France",
                "Australia",
                "New Zealand"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "61.\u2018Santiago Pe\u00f1a\u2019 recently became the President of which country?",
            "options": [
                "Suda",
                "Paraguay",
                "Brazil",
                "Canada"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Paraguay"
        },
        {
            "question": "62.Which department manages the \u2018Swachhata Pakhwada\u2019 event?",
            "options": [
                "Department of Agriculture and Farmers Welfare.",
                "Department of Drinking Water and Sanitation.",
                "Department of Publication",
                "Department of Drinking Water and Sanitation."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Department of Drinking Water and Sanitation."
        },
        {
            "question": "63.After nine-year ban, Coal mining has resumed legally in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Assam",
                "Meghalaya",
                "West Bengal",
                "Odisha"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Meghalaya"
        },
        {
            "question": "64.The US and which country agreed on new immigration policies to prevent illegal bordercrossing?",
            "options": [
                "Canada",
                "Mexico",
                "Cuba",
                "El-Salvador"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Mexico"
        },
        {
            "question": "65.The Central Government has informed the Supreme Court that it will form a panel on same-sexcouples headed by?",
            "options": [
                "Union Home Minister",
                "Cabinet Secretary",
                "NITI Aayog CEO",
                "Union Women and Child Development Minister"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Cabinet Secretary"
        },
        {
            "question": "67.What is India\u2019s rank in the \u2018World Press Freedom Index 2023\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "141",
                "151",
                "161",
                "171"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "161"
        },
        {
            "question": "68.Which term denotes the new type of chemical bonding in solids?",
            "options": [
                "Metavalent Bonding",
                "Quadravalent Bonding",
                "Pentavalent Bonding",
                "Ultravalent Bonding"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Metavalent Bonding"
        },
        {
            "question": "69.What is the name of the \u2018Festival of Innovation in Arts\u2019, which was launched on WorldIntellectual Property Day?",
            "options": [
                "ATAL",
                "UPAJ",
                "NIPUN",
                "MAHAN"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "UPAJ"
        },
        {
            "question": "70.\u2018Ekatha Harbour\u2019 is the biggest Indian grant-in-aid projects in which country?",
            "options": [
                "Bangladesh",
                "Maldives",
                "Nepal",
                "Myanmar"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Maldives"
        },
        {
            "question": "71. Which institution released a report on Currency and Finance?",
            "options": [
                "NITI Aayog",
                "RBI",
                "NPCI",
                "SEBI"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "RBI"
        },
        {
            "question": "72.\u2018Fake News Law, also known as the Bill 2630\u2019 is the proposed legislation in which country?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "Brazil",
                "New Zealand",
                "Bangladesh"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "73.Which institution released the \u201cGeoeconomic Fragmentation: Sub-Saharan Africa Caughtbetween the Fault Lines\u201d Report?",
            "options": [
                "WEF",
                "IMF",
                "ADB",
                "AIIB"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IMF"
        },
        {
            "question": "74.\u2018Kyasanur Forest Disease\u2019 has been recorded in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Goa",
                "Karnataka",
                "West Bengal",
                "Sikkim"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Karnataka"
        },
        {
            "question": "75.Which state\/UT launched a dedicated website for food safety and mobile app for consumers?",
            "options": [
                "Odisha",
                "Tamil Nadu",
                "Goa",
                "Assam"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Tamil Nadu"
        },
        {
            "question": "76.What is the name of the eclipse, when the Moon moves through the outer part of the Earth'sshadow?",
            "options": [
                "Partial lunar Eclipse",
                "Penumbral lunar Eclipse",
                "Total lunar Eclipse",
                "Central lunar Eclipse"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Penumbral lunar Eclipse"
        },
        {
            "question": "77.Which country\/region\u2019s regulator derecognised six Indian central counterparties?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "Australia",
                "European Union",
                "Germany"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "European Union"
        },
        {
            "question": "78.Indira Gandhi Mahila Samman Nidhi was launched in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Rajasthan",
                "Himachal Pradesh",
                "Chhattisgarh",
                "Meghalaya"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Himachal Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "79.Which state\/UT has recently set up a \u2018Directorate of Minority Affairs\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Sikkim",
                "Nagaland",
                "West Bengal",
                "Odisha"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Nagaland"
        },
        {
            "question": "81.Horaglanis populi, which was found in Kerala, belongs to which species?",
            "options": [
                "Fish",
                "Spider",
                "Snake",
                "Turtle"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Fish"
        },
        {
            "question": "82.What is the name of the inaugural cargo ship to the Myanmar\u2019s Sittwe Port?",
            "options": [
                "MV-ITT LION (V-273)",
                "MV-ITT TIGER (V-273)",
                "MV-ITT BULL (V-273)",
                "MV-ITT CHEETAH (V-273)"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "MV-ITT LION (V-273)"
        },
        {
            "question": "83.As per the \u2018Global Warming\u2019s Four Indias, 2022\u2019, what percent of Indians are concerned aboutGlobal warming?",
            "options": [
                "58 %",
                "62 %",
                "72 %",
                "82 %"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "82 %"
        },
        {
            "question": "84.\u2018Global Network Against Food Crisis\u2019 was founded in which year?",
            "options": [
                "2012",
                "2016",
                "2020",
                "2024"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "2016"
        },
        {
            "question": "85.\u2018STATCOM\u2019, which was seen in the news recently, is associated with which field?",
            "options": [
                "Cryptocurrency",
                "Renewable Energy",
                "Sports",
                "Automobile"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Renewable Energy"
        },
        {
            "question": "86.\u2018Vaisakh Purnima\u2019 is associated with which religion?",
            "options": [
                "Hinduism",
                "Jainism",
                "Buddhism",
                "Jainism"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Buddhism"
        },
        {
            "question": "87.Which state has set up a \u2018High-Level Committee on Restructuring and Re-organisation of StatePolice\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Assam",
                "Nagaland",
                "West Bengal",
                "Odisha"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Nagaland"
        },
        {
            "question": "88.Prevention of Money Laundering Act (PMLA) was enacted in which year?",
            "options": [
                "1992",
                "2002",
                "2012",
                "2022"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "2002"
        },
        {
            "question": "90.Which is the first US state to ban fossil fuels in New Buildings?",
            "options": [
                "New York",
                "Chicago",
                "Boston",
                "Detroit"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "New York"
        },
        {
            "question": "91.Dawki landport, which was recently inaugurated, is located between India and which country?",
            "options": [
                "Myanmar",
                "Nepal",
                "Bangladesh",
                "Sri Lanka"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Bangladesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "92.Which Indian Naval Ship has been decommissioned after 36 years of service?",
            "options": [
                "INS Magar",
                "INS Mahaan",
                "INS Vihaan",
                "INS Bhim"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "INS Magar"
        },
        {
            "question": "93.Which country hosted the \u2018Machines Can See 2023 Summit\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "USA",
                "Israel",
                "UAE"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "UAE"
        },
        {
            "question": "95.The Battlefield Surveillance System is associated with which Armed Force?",
            "options": [
                "Indian Air Force",
                "Indian Army",
                "Indian Navy",
                "Indian Coast Guard"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Indian Army"
        },
        {
            "question": "96.The \u201cClinical Trial Opportunities in India Report\u201d has been released by PwC India in associationwith which institution?",
            "options": [
                "World Bank",
                "AIIMS",
                "USAIC",
                "Niti Aayog"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USAIC"
        },
        {
            "question": "97.Where is the India-Sri Lanka Friendship Auditorium being set up?",
            "options": [
                "Mumbai",
                "Chennai",
                "Rameshwaram",
                "Trincomalee"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Trincomalee"
        },
        {
            "question": "98.The Amazon Fund is maintained by which financial institution?",
            "options": [
                "World Bank",
                "IMF",
                "New Development Bank",
                "Brazilian Development Bank"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Brazilian Development Bank"
        },
        {
            "question": "99.Where is the COP 28 scheduled to be held?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "Dubai",
                "USA",
                "Japan"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Dubai"
        },
        {
            "question": "100.MoHUA has signed a MoU with which organisation, for technical assistance under the SwachhBharat Mission-Urban 2.0?",
            "options": [
                "ISRO",
                "DRDO",
                "RITES",
                "Indian Army"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "RITES"
        }
    ]
}